# VALDIS **Kalejs**

3822 Markridge Rd, La Crescenta, CA 91214 | H: 213-923-7682 | valdiskalejs55@gmail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Personable and reliable IT Field Service Technician offering 20+ years of experience working in deadline-oriented environments.

Well-developed skills in installation, repair, maintenance and customer service.

Technically-advanced information technology specialist successful in software administration and data communications.

### **SKILLS**

- Report generation
- Documentation and reporting
- Work order management
- Troubleshooting and repair
- Exceptional Customer Service
- Operational support
- Vendor contracts and relationships
- Computers and electronics
- Information technology
- Strong collaborative skills

- Proficiency in TCP/IP protocols
- Wifi installation/configuring and troubleshooting
- Deal with System Avaya Call Manager
- Program, install and repair IP and TDM type phones
- Program voice and info mailboxes
- Program various user features such as meet-me conference, ec500, auto attendants, incoming call-blocking, holiday and TOD schedules
- Program call routing internally and externally
- Interface with vendor on trunk problems such as trunk alarms, exchange code dialing problems, etc
- Provide user training and assistance on system/phone features

#### **EXPERIENCE**

05/1998 to 08/2019

## Field Service Engineer

**University Of Southern California** — Los Angeles, CA

- Input information from customer calls and onsite service visits into the company's system using [SNOW and Pinnacle].
- Manage day-to-day operations and maintenance of equipment in IT department.
- Work on completing work tickets regarding: Networking issues/activations/moves

Network switch /router Installation and troubleshooting

VOIP/ISDN/Analog phone installations upgrades and troubleshooting Wireless installation and troubleshooting

- 10 years of experience troubleshooting wireless/data wireless routers and switches
  - Desktop installation upgrades and troubleshooting
- Worked as an IT liaison for USC's Galen Center for all events that required IT/wireless/phones
- Worked on oncall rotation dealing with pressing IT networking wifi issues

#### 05/1996 to 05/1998

## **Network Engineer**

University Of Southern California — Los Angeles, CA

- Employed knowledge of data network technology and infrastructures to develop effective solutions.
- Performed and documented network operations using step-by-step decision trees.
- Established and maintained network systems using networking principles.

• Maximized network availability and performance by monitoring, troubleshooting, resolving outages and scheduling upgrades.

11/2019 to 11/2019

**Prinnter Installer Murtech Consultine** — Los Angeles, CA
Installed new printers At State Farm offices

## **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

**High School Diploma Crescenta Valley High School** — La Crescenta, CA